# Dr TAN Hong Ming

My academic and professional endeavors have given me a unique perspective on the intersection of academia and industry, particularly in the fields of Analytics, Operations Research, and Al. I lead teams of data scientists and PhD students, consult for companies on Al and data science applications, and teach Al across all levels, from undergraduates to MBA, EMBA and executive programs.

## Work Experience

University of Singapore

O Management and Supervision of Department

Automation of Business School Processes

2023–Present Al Advisor, Nexus Homes

O Al and Data strategy and development

2021–Present Co-Founder, ECHE Pte Ltd

O Consulting for AI, Data Science, and Operations

2023-Present Lead Al Advisor, XOPA Al

O Advise CEO, CTO, and co-founders on company AI strategy and focus

O Advise and lead team of Data Scientists

O Invited speaker for webinar on the use of AI in recruitment, hosted by APSCo Asia

2024-Present **Senior Lecturer**, *Department of Analytics and Operations*, NUS Business School, National University of Singapore

 Principal investigator - Optimising Maritime Network Line Design using Reinforcement Learning (S\$384,000)

o Co-PI: Al-led Smart Data Centre Management Application (S\$330,000)

 Collaborator with Institute of Mental Health on Screening and Invervention of Depression (Lead for Machine Learning and AI development, S\$1,000,000)

O NUS Business School Teaching Excellence Award 2023

O Chair of Department Finance Committee

Member of Department Teaching Committee

O Statistics Primer Workshops for MSc programs in Business School

Economics Bootcamp for MSc Business Analytics

O Executive Education: Al for Leaders: Leveraging Data Analytics For Business

O Executive Education: General Management Programme

O BME5202 - Opportunities in AI (EMBA)

BMA5278 - Business Insights through Industry Analysis (MBA)

O PHM5014 - Causal Inference in Precision Medicine (MSc)

O PHM5006 – Ethics, Regulation and Managerial Economics In Precision Medicine (MSc)

O DBA3803 Predictive Analytics in Business (UG)

O DAO1704 Decision Analytics Using Spreadsheets (UG)

Faculty Advisor for Business Analytics Consulting Team

Faculty Advisor for NUS Private Equity Society

- 2021–2023 **Lecturer**, *Department of Analytics and Operations*, NUS Business School, National University of Singapore
  - O Chair of Department Finance Committee
  - O Member of Department Teaching Committee
  - O BMA5275 Analytics in Managerial Economics (MBA)
  - O BME5201 Leading with Analytics (EMBA)
  - o DAO1704 Decision Analytics Using Spreadsheets (UG)
    - Awarded SGD50,000 to redevelop module for Blended Learning 2.0
  - o Executive Education: Leading with Big Data Analytics and Machine Learning
  - O Pioneered the Teaching Training Program for PhD students
  - Practical Decision Making Using Data Science Online Executive Education course by Great Learning
  - o Faculty Advisor for Business Analytics Consulting Team
  - o Faculty Advisor for NUS Private Equity Society
- 2021–2024 Research Fellow (Project Manager), Institute of Operations Research and Analytics, National University of Singapore
  - SIA-NUS Corp Lab
    - Project Manager for Transforming Competency and Skill Development using AI and Analytics (leading team of 3 PhD students and multiple Research Assistants)
  - Collaborator of SGD1,000,000 grant with Institute of Mental Health on Screening and Invervention of Depression (Lead Machine Learning effort)
  - O Project Manager for Multiple Industry Projects with leading Global Medical Device Company
    - Quality Control
    - Text Analytics
    - Manages team of Research Assistants
  - O NUS GRIP Venture Hothouse participant
  - 2020 **Visiting Research Student**, *Institute for Data, Systems, and Society*, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
- 2020–2023 Programme Leader, Emeritus Institute of Management
  - Business Analytics for Strategic Decisions
  - Python for Analytics
- 2017–2021 **PhD Candidate**, *Institute of Operations Research and Analytics*, National University of Singapore
  - O Lead for Field Studies of Pilot training Project for a Major Airline Carrier
  - O Lead for Demand Modeling and Price Optimization Project for a Major Airline Carrier
  - Lead for Forecasting Possible Quality Issues and Optimal Responses to the Forecasts for a Leading Global Medical Device Company
  - O Instructor for DSC5101 Analytics in Managerial Economics
  - O Instructor for Executive Education: Leading with Big Data Analytics and Machine Learning
  - o Teaching Assistant for DSC5101 Analytics in Managerial Economics
  - O Tutor for DAO1704/DSC1007 Decision Analytics Using Spreadsheets
  - Outstanding Graduate Student Teaching Award
  - o MSOM 2019 Conference and SIG Meeting Local Organising Committee
  - O Analytics for X Conference 2021 Local Organising Committee
- 2015–2017 **Graduate Research Student**, *Department of Mathematics*, Faculty of Science, National University of Singapore
  - O Completed Training Programme for Teaching Assistants
  - O Tutor for MA1505 Mathematics I
  - Tutor for MA1101R Linear Algebra I
  - O Achieved top 20% of all graduate tutors in teaching performance

- 2013–2015 Lecturer, Mathematics and Statistics Division, Temasek Polytechnic
  - Collaborated with NUS Pharmaceutical Science to create interactive webpages using HTML5 elements and Javascript
  - Co-authored three textbooks
  - Coordinated Online Student Evaluation of Teaching Effectiveness system for the School of Applied Science
  - O Subject Leader for the subject "Statistics for Applied Science"
  - O Completed Teaching in Higher Education Certificate
  - O Completed Data Analytics in Healthcare course
  - O Completed WSQ 3D Printing for Rapid Product Development course
  - 2009 Administrative Assistant, Office of Undergraduate Programmes, NUS Faculty of Engineering
    - Organizing Committee of Fourteenth National Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme 2009
    - O Coordinated Industrial Attachment and Vacation Internship Programme
    - O Assisted with Student Exchange Programme
  - 2008 **Defensive Computer Warfare/Information Assurance Platoon Commander**, 18C4 Unit, Singapore Armed Forces, Lieutenant
    - O Managed and oversee the integrity of SAF's computer and network security
    - O Coordinated the audit of Top Secret and Secret classified documents for all SAF Joint forces

#### Awards

- 2023 National University of Singapore, NUS Business School, NUS Business School Teaching Excellence Award 2023
- 2019 **National University of Singapore**, *Department of Analytics and Operations*, Outstanding Graduate Student Teaching Award
- 2017 **National University of Singapore**, *Department of Mathematics*, Graduate Programme in Mathematics by Research, Letter of Commendation for Graduate Tutor
- 2004 Singapore Mathematical Olympiads, Senior Section, Bronze Award

## Research Papers and Published Works

- Accepted **EcoVal: An Efficient Data Valuation Framework for Machine Learning**, Ayush Kumar Tarun, Bowei Chen, Hong Ming Tan, Vikram Singh Chundawat, Mohan Kankanhalli, Murari Mandal, KDD 2024
- Published Transdiagnostic Clustering of Self-Schema from Self-Referential Judgements identifies subtypes of healthy Personality and Depression, Tan, G. C. -Y., Wang, Z., Tan, E. S. E., Ong, R. J. M., Ooi, P. E., Lee, D., . . . Keppo, J. (2024), FRONTIERS IN NEUROINFORMATICS, 17, 19 pages. http://doi.org/10.3389/fninf.2023.1244347
- Published Comparing feature selection and machine learning approaches for predicting CYP2D6 methylation from genetic variation, Fong, W. J., Tan, H. M., Garg, R., Teh, A. L., Pan, H., Gupta, V., . . . Tan, G. C. -Y. (2024), FRONTIERS IN NEUROINFORMATICS, 17, 16 pages. http://doi.org/10.3389/fninf.2023.1244336
- Published **Evaluation of a New Antiresistic Strategy to Manage Antibiotic Resistance**, *Hong Ming Tan, Ambika C. Lall, Jussi Keppo, Swaine L. Chen (2023)*, Journal of Global Antimicrobial Resistance, Volume 33, 2023, Pages 368-375, ISSN 2213-7165
- Published Chapter The Case Method and Technology: Applying the Seven Principles for Good Practice in Undergraduate Education in a Business School Course, Tan, H. M. (2023), Designing Technology-Mediated Case Learning in Higher Education: A Global Perspective (pp. 17-31). Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore.
- Published A modification to Pull the Goalie that takes into account the state of play: Coach Markov returns, Zaman, Z. and Tan, H. M. (2020), CHANCE, 33(1), 10-15

- Working Risky Investments under Static and Dynamic Information Acquisition, Keppo, Jussi Paper and Tan, Hong Ming and Zhou, Chao, https://ssrn.com/abstract=3141043
- Working Fare Ladder Optimization: Airline Revenue Management in Volatile Environment,
  Paper Changchun Liu, Hong Ming Tan, Chung-Piaw Teo, Gang Guo, Yan Chen, Tim Lee
  2023 CSAMSE Practice Award Finalist
- Working Flying High with Improved Data: How an Instructor Training Workshop Boosting
  Paper Pilot Competency Assessment, Qingyin Ge, Jussi Keppo, Chuan Hoo Tan, Hong Ming
  Tan
- Working Dynamic Pricing in the Airline Industry: Theory and Practice, Chung Khim Lae, Hong Paper Ming Tan, Bar Light, Jussi Keppo
- Working Data Science Approach to Process Control, Yuda Ho, Jussi Keppo, Ek Hong Lim, Paper Herman Tan, and Hong Ming Tan
- Working An Analytic Framework for Detecting Emerging Defects through Active Learning, Paper Lu, B., Dong, Y., Ying, Y., Tan, H. and Keppo, J.

## Academic Qualifications

- 2017–2021 **Ph.D. in Operations Research and Analytics**, *Institute of Operations Research and Analytics*, National University of Singapore
- 2015–2017 **Master of Science by Research**, *Department of Mathematics*, Faculty of Science, National University of Singapore
  - O Graduate Programme in Mathematics by Research
  - O Thesis Title: Investment and the Quantity of Data Analytics
- 2009–2013 **Bachelor of Science(Hons)**, *National University of Singapore*, Second Class Honours, Upper Division
  - Applied Mathematics (Primary Major)
  - Economics (Second Major)
  - o CAP 4.29/5